Alexander Pierce

Eagan, MN 55123 | alecpierce19@gmail.com | https://alterproject.space

Overview:

I'm a Full Stack Software Engineer with 7+ years of experience coding in enterprise-scale applications using Angular, Java, and JVM Languages such as Scala, Kotlin, and Groovy. I have experience in leading frontend development and mentoring junior Angular developers. I am conscious of the need to document, test, and keep track of work in software development. I consider myself a team player and excited to learn new things daily.

Work Experience:

Cognizant Softvision – Senior Software Engineer

Jun 2021 - Aug 2024

- Built multiple front-end applications from the ground up using Angular as the lead web developer
- Engineered an infinite scrolling reusable component for an in-house npm library to display paginated data
- Implemented reactive web pages based on Figma designs created by Product Managers and UX Designers
- Collaborated closely with management and team members to translate requirements into JIRA stories
- Migrated existing repositories while preserving historical data using GIT
- Optimized the search performance for paginated search result tables
- Assumed leadership responsibilities to maintain project delivery timelines and run agile ceremonies during leadership transitions
- Achieved position of lead knowledge expert regarding legacy application functionalities within the team
- Resolved data conversion challenges that occurred with existing DocuSign integration
- Created forms to be used for web applications in Adobe Acrobat Pro
- Performed code reviews to meet client standards and gave feedback using Gitlab
- Presented a small proof of concept for session management using Redis and Docker
- Addressed compliance issues by rectifying CWEs discovered with Veracode static analysis tool
- Investigated and resolved memory leak issues caused by a PDF displayer dependency by analyzing metrics in Datadog and examining Java heap dumps

Virgin Pulse – Associate Software Engineer

Jan 2019 – Dec 2020

- Developed admin tools for portal use incorporating Angular2 on the frontend and Java on the backend, while transitioning java classes and services to Kotlin
- Maintained full stack legacy applications, server pipelines, builds, and deployments to production ensuring stable builds and environments using Rundeck, TeamCity, and GitLab
- Implemented WCAG guidelines and accessibility features to legacy applications, enhancing user experience and compliance for client
- Led agile ceremonies on a rotational basis and mentored new interns through technical challenges

Maverick Software Consulting – Software Engineer Intern

Apr 2017 – Dec 2018

- Resolved XML conversion bugs across lower environments and production
- Developed, maintained, and tested new conversion modules utilizing HTML/JSON parsers
- Converted existing projects to Java 8 with a focus on maintaining backward compatibility with Java 6

Education:

Minnesota State University, Mankato

Dec 2018

Bachelor of Science: Management Information Systems

Graph Developer – Associate Certificate

May 2023

ID: d11e2f7a-4a53-4905-891f-35f1c5fd2c9f

Skills:

- Backend Technologies: Java, Spring, GraphQL, Scala, Groovy, Kotlin, PostgreSQL
- Frontend Technologies: Typescript, Angular2, CDK, MaterialUI, HTML5, SCSS, JSON, Jest, Reactjs
- Development Tools: GIT, Bitbucket, Azure DevOps, JIRA, TFS, SVN, Bash